A Finding Aid to the Lilian Swann Saarinen Papers, circa 1909-1977, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1920-1974; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.9 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, 8, OV 12
  - First Names Only, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Barbara, Ben, Bobbie, 1940-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Camilla, Casanova, Cavannas, Charles, Claus, circa 1940s-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Dorothy, Doda, circa 1930s-1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Doda letter encloses childhood drawings by Swann Saarinen
    - Ed, Fran, Fred, circa 1940-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Gardner, Greta, Herman, Hildy, 1940s-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Jack, Jean, Jeanne, Jessie, John, circa 1939-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Kenneth, Kiki, Kim, Louise, circa 1931-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Margaret, Marilyn, Marjorie, Marlee, Mary, circa 1941-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Nell, Norma, Olga, 1934-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Pamela, Peter, Poppy, Prestin, 1930s-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - R, Illegible, Roland, S, Illegible, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - T, Illegible, Tom, Val, William (Bill), Willy, circa 1940s-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Fragments of Letters from Lily Swann Saarinen, circa 1930s-circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Illegible/Unidentified, circa 1940s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Oversized Eames, Charles and Ray scanned with Box 1, Folder 20, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Hammond, Susan and Paul scanned with Box 1, Folder 37, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Saarinen, Eero scanned with Box 2 Folders 31 and 34, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Oversized First Names Only, Barbara, Be, Bobbie, scanned with Box 2, Folder 56, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Oversized First Names Only, Jack, Jean, Jeanne, Jessie, John scanned with Box 2, Folder 61, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Cavin, W. Brooks Jr. scanned with Box 1, Folder 12, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 12)
  - Oversized Koch, Carl scanned with Box 1, Folder 48, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 12)
  - Oversized Midtown Galleries scanned with Box 2, Folder 10, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 12)
- Writings and Notes, 1920s-1973; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 2-3, 8, OVs 13-16
  Writings and notes document the writing and publication of Saarinen's Picture Book Zoo and Who Am I?, as well as Saarinen's ideas in draft, typescript and sketch form for other publications such as "Animals and War Machines," a proposed follow-up to Who Am I? titled "Who Helps Who?" and other children's writings such as "Susie Sing All Day" and "What Is Mine?" Documentation consists of correspondence with publishers, drafts and typsecripts of texts, original artwork including preliminary sketches, photos of artwork, and book layouts.
  Also found are school writings from the 1920s-1930s; typescripts and handwritten drafts of Saarinen's memories of the Cranbrook Academy of Art, Eliel Saarinen, and the Saarinen family; and miscellaneous writings which include "Sculpture by American Soldiers" in which Saarinen drew on her 1945 experience teaching convalescent soldiers.
  - Anatomy Notebook, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - "Animals and War Machines" Book Ideas, circa 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - "Animals and War Machines" Book Ideas, circa 1943-circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - "Animals and War Machines" Book Idea, Preliminary Sketches, circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - "Animals and War Machines" Book Idea, Preliminary Sketches, circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - "Animals and War Machines" Book Idea, Preliminary Sketches, circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - "Animals and War Machines" Book Idea, Preliminary Sketches, circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 76)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 2 and OV 13
  - "Miscellaneous Secret Thoughts and Writings of Mine", 1929-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1930s-1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1930s-1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous, 1930s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Other Book Ideas, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Picture Book Zoo, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
    - Artwork, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sketches, Hippos, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Published Copy, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Quotations and Thoughts and Animal Records (in back) from Winter with Saunders", 1929-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Reminiscences about Eliel Saarinen for Nancy Rivard, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Reminiscences about the Saarinen Family and Cranbrook Art Academy, circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - School Writings, 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Susie Sing All Day", circa 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Oversized material housed in OV 14
  - "What is Mine?", 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Who Am I?, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Notes, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Notes, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Notes and Typescripts, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Original Artwork, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 3 and OV 15
    - Photographs of Artwork, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Oversized material housed in OVs 13 and 16
    - Proof, circa 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Sketches, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Sketches, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Sketches, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 3
    - Sketches for Flyleaf, circa 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Who Helps Who?", Archival Resource Key
    - Artwork, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Artwork, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Artwork, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Sketches and Notes, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Sketches and Notes, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Oversized "Animals and War Machines" Book Idea, Preliminary Sketches scanned with Box 2, Folder 76, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Who Am I?, Original Artwork scanned with Box 3, Folder 20, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Who Am I?, Sketches, scanned with Box 3, Folder 25, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Oversized "Animals and War Machines," Book Idea, Preliminary Sketches scanned with Box 2, Folder 76, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 13)
  - Oversized Who Am I?, Photos of Artwork scanned with Box 3, Folder 21, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 13)
  - Oversized "Susie Sing All Day" scanned with Box 3, Folder 14, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 14)
  - Oversized Who Am I?, Original Artwork scanned with Box 3, Folder 20, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 15)
  - Oversized Who Am I?, Photos of Artwork scanned with Box 3, Folder 21, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 16)
- Diaries, 1930-1973; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 3-5, 8
  Saarinen was a prolific journal writer and her diaries are in bound volume and loose leaf form. Bound diary volumes from 1930/1931 to 1942 document her life from her "coming out year" and continue through the early years of her marriage to Eero Saarinen. Her 1939 diary opens in Florence, Italy, in August 1939, days before Germany's invasion of Poland, and describes the tenuous situation the newlyweds found themselves in and their difficulties finding passage back to the United States. The diary labeled 1936 and 1937 also contains a series of entries for 1958-1959. Written on the page at the front of the 1939 December-1942 January is the inscription: "Diary-Cranbrook from Sept 1939 To:" and "The new Mrs. E. E. Saarinen!" but any original pages that existed from September-November are missing. The months August-October 1939 are included in the previous diary.
  Loose diary entries, beginning around circa 1934 and continuing to 1953, with scattered additional entries in the 1950s-1970s, focus primarily on Saarinen's marriage to Eero Saarinen. They document in depth her emotional struggles as a working mother attempting to forge her own artistic identity, maintain a healthy family environment for her children, and support Eero Saarinen's growing international success, while not allowing that to stymie her own artistic ambitions. These folders include many handwritten notes and drafts of "letters" to Eero Saarinen which are journalistic in nature and include dream journals, "writings and ravings just before wedding," and notes found with her diaries.
  Saarinen's engagement calendars are heavily annotated with notes documenting her professional appointments, progress on works of art and commissions, and Saarinen's leisure activities.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of blank pages of diaries and unannotated pages of engagement calendars.
  Some of the diary entries within volumes are not strictly chronological and often do not occur in a linear fashion.
  - Addresses, circa 1940s-circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Bound Diary Volume, 1930-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Bound Diary Volume (1934-1935), 1934 July-October; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Bound Diary Volume (1934-1935), 1934 October-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bound Diary Volume (1934-1935), 1935 January-June; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Bound Diary Volume (1934-1935), Miscellaneous Pages, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Bound Diary Volume, 1935-1936 October; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Bound Diary Volume (1936-1937, 1958-1959), 1936-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Bound Diary Volume, 1939 August-October; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bound Diary Volume, 1939 December-1942 January; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Diary of Greece and the Dalmation Coast, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Diary of Greece and the Dalmation Coast, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1938, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1940, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1942, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1949, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1951, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1953, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1958, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Engagement Calendars, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Loose Diary Entries and Fragments, circa 1934-circa 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 4
  - Loose Diary Entries and Fragments, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Loose Diary Entries and Fragments, circa 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Loose Diary Entries and Fragments, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Loose Diary Entries and Fragments, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Loose Diary Entries and Fragments, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Loose Diary Entries and Fragments, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Fragments, circa 1940s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Notes Found with Diaries, 1930s-1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Notes Found with Diaries, 1930s-1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Notes Found with Diaries, 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Notes Found with Diaries, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Notes Found with Diaries, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Notes Found with Diaries, 1940-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Notes Found with Diaries, 1952-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Notes Written Prior to Wedding, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Oversized Loose Diary Entries and Fragments scanned with Box 4, Folder 21, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Project Files, 1931-1966; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 5-6, 8, OVs 17-19
  Project files are arranged alphabetically by name of project.
  Project files document Saarinen's work on a variety of commissions including those for book cover designs, federal government buildings, post offices, schools and playgrounds (particularly the Crow Island School reliefs), companies such as KLM (then Royal Dutch Airlines), businesses such as Toffenetti's restaurant in Chicago, and private clients, including sister-in-law, Pipsan Saarinen. The majority of the projects documented here resulted in fully realized commissions for Saarinen, although several represent ideas and proposals.
  Project files typically contain any and all of the following: correspondence and notes, many preliminary sketches, plans and blueprints, and photographs of artwork and project sites, with the bulk of the material being in the form of sketches. Sketches are primarily in graphite, although some are hand-colored with ink and/or paint.
  Crow Island school sketches are arranged alphabetically by subject, primarily animals.
  - Addison Gallery, Hippo Sketches, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Barn Dance, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Barns, Katrina McCormick Sculpture, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Bloomfield, Indiana, Post Office, circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 5
  - Book Cover for New Directions in Prose and Poetry, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Book Cover for The White Mule, circa 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Book Ideas for Farrar & Rinehart, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Carlisle, Kentucky, Post Office Sculpture, Correspondence, 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Carlisle, Kentucky, Post Office Sculpture, Sketches, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Carlisle, Kentucky, Post Office Sculpture, Sketches, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Carlisle, Kentucky, Post Office Sculpture, Sketches, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Ceramic Pig, circa 1941-circa 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 6
  - Children's Magazine (Child Life?), Chipmunks, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Children's Playground, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Crow Island School, Winnetka, Illinois, Archival Resource Key (Box 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 7 and OV 20
    - File List and Photographs, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
      Oversized material housed in Box 8, folder 7
    - Anteater, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Bear, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Bull, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Cow, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Deer and Duck Bill, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Elephant and Eero's Sketches, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
      Oversized material housed in OV 17
    - Frog and Ferdinand, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Glaze Records and Brick Sizes/Class Subjects, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Horse, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Indian Group (Squirrel, Owl, Horned Toad, Ram, Indians), circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Lion and Mouse, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Monkeys and Mowgli, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Noah, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Opossum, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Pekingese and Pig, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Prehistoric Animals, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Rabbit, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Rikki Tikki Tavi, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Sloth and Squirrel, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Weasel, circa 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Other Ideas, Costs, etc., Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Cushion Ideas, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Evanston, Illinois, Post Office, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Evanston, Illinois, Post Office, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Evanston, Illinois, Post Office, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 54)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 8 and OV 18
  - Federal Trade Commission (Apex) Building, Washington D. C., circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Federal Trade Commission (Apex) Building, Washington D. C., circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 56)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 9
  - Gateway Arch, St. Louis, Missouri, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 57)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 10
  - Harbor National Bank Clock, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Harbor National Bank Clock, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Harbor National Bank Clock, 1964-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 60)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 11
  - KLM Airlines Sculpture, JFK Airport, circa 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 61)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 12 and OV 18
  - Museum of Modern Art Competition, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Northland Center, Detroit, Michigan, Correspondence, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Northland Center, Detroit, Michigan, Correspondence, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Northland Center, Detroit, Michigan, Printed Material, circa 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Northland Center, Detroit, Michigan, Sketches and Photographs of Artwork, circa 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 66)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 13 and OV 18
  - Red Cross, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Red Cross, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 68)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 14
  - Rome Collaborative Ideas, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Saarinen, Pipsan, Fireplace, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Saarinen, Pipsan, Fireplace, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Toffenetti's Restaurant, Chicago, Illinois, Correspondence, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Toffenetti's Restaurant, Chicago, Illinois, Photographs, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 73)
    Includes photo of Saarinen working on sculpture; oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 15 and OV 19
  - Toffenetti's Restaurant, Chicago, Illinois, Sketches, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Toffenetti's Restaurant, Chicago, Illinois, Sketches and Metal Cut-Out, circa 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 75)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 15 and OV 19
  - Various Project Sketches, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, Folder 16
  - War Department Competition, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - War Department Competition, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - War Department Competition, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Bloomfield, Indiana, Post Office scanned with Box 5, Folder 18, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Ceramic Pig scanned with Box 5, Folder 26, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Crow Island School, Winnetka, IL, File List and Photographs scanned with Box 5, Folder 29, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Evanston, Illinois, Post Office scanned with Box 5, Folder 54, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Federal Trade Commission (Apex) Building, Washington D. C scanned with Box 5, Folder 56, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Oversized Gateway Arch, St. Louis, Missouri scanned with Box 5, Folder 57, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Oversized Harbor National Bank Clock scanned with Box 5, Folder 60, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Oversized KLM Airlines Sculpture, JFK Airport scanned with Box 5, Folder 61, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Northland Center, Detroit, Michigan scanned with Box 5, Folder 66, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Oversized Red Cross scanned with Box 5, Folder 68, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Oversized Toffenetti's Restaurant, Chicago, Illinois, Photographs and Sketches scanned with Box 5, Folders 73 and 75, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Oversized Various Project Sketches scanned with Box 6, Folder 1, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Oversized Crow Island School, Winnetka, IL, Sketches and Notes, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 17)
    - Elephant, Eero's Sketches scanned with Box 5, Folder 35, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 17)
    - Noah scanned with Box 5, Folder 42, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 17)
    - Opossum scanned with Box 5, Folder 43, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 17)
    - Prehistoric Animals scanned with Box 5, Folder 45, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 17)
    - Rikki Tikki Tavi scanned with Box 5, Folder 47, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 17)